Oliver Camones

Kansas City, MO ocamonesv@uni.pe 210-900-6725

https://ocamones.github.io/OliverCamones/

Personal Summary

Entry-level Data Analyst with 1+ years of experience analyzing big data and visualizing data. Looking to apply my experience with BI Tool and System Design and Python Programming at your company before pursuing a Master's Degree in Information Technology as a complement to my science degree.

Key Skills

- Python
- Javascript
- SQL
- PowerBl
- Tableu
- Microsoft Office 365
- Deep Process Modeling
- Bilingual Spanish/ English
- Analytical
- Innovative
- Problem Solving

Professional Experience

Lab Analyst-Data Analyst

SGS (Société Générale de Surveillance) Callao, Peru

May 2022 — May 2023

- Implemented new Power BI models to summarize work hours, automate additional KPIs, statistically analyze results, and control documents.
- Developed an application to log work hours and increase accountability.
- Developed a Deep Process Model that created a statistical and visual analysis of imported results. My program increased client satisfaction and resulted in high contract renewal.
- Programmed a model to compile and summarize worker training from over 40 Excel spreadsheets, resulting in easier KAI Training tracking.

Lab Analyst

SGS, (Société Générale de Surveillance) Callao, Peru

Mar 2021 — May 2022

- Devised algorithms in Excel to optimize procedures by converting manual workflow into a digital format.
- Collaborated with a team to develop algorithms and programs to automate data analysis.

Junior Lab Analyst

SGS (Société Générale de Surveillance) Callao, Peru

Aug 2019 — Mar 2021

- Conducted Granulometry Analysis using Macros. Programed relevant criteria to easily analyze and visualize data, which increased productivity over 200%.
- Introduced Power BI Desktop for KPIs in SGS to efficiently consolidate data.

Education

Bachelor of Science in Chemical Engineering

National University of Engineering, Lima, Peru | 2013 — 2018

Certifications

- ¥ Data Analyst-SQL, Power BI, Python
 WE Execute Education (WE Educación Ejecutiva)
- ¥ Microsoft Specialist Business Excel- Excel, Power Query, Power BI Education (Cámara del Comercio Exterior)
- ¥ Lead Implementer of Integrated HSEQ ISO Management Systems ISO 9001, ISO 14001, ISO 45001
 BSG Institute